so, I am just gonna look at my screen
大家请看我的大屏幕
anyways, so, I am here to talk about harnessing the awesome power of streems
好，今天我要和大家聊聊：如何充分利用stream的超强威力
uh, streams are I think the most underused part of Node
我觉得stream是Node中最未被充分利用的一部分
and they are what makes Node and JavaScript in general really really amazing
但总体说来，却正是stream，赋予了Node以及JavaScript不可思议的魔力
so, back in the sixties, uh, sort of this recurring trope
回到六十年代，这里要反复强调
no, I can't, shut up!
不，别想了，闭嘴！（台下不知发生何事）
so, back in the sixties, this, this guy, Doug..., actual "I" can't make vigor
好，回到六十年代，有个叫Doug……，事实上重音不能在“I”上
this guy, Doug McIlroy
有个叫Doug McIlroy的家伙
uh, was like kind of , uh, like, put his folder on the ground, whatever that is and said:
貌似，貌似，将文件夹摔在地上（随便吧，不重要），怒斥道：
no, Unix is gonna have Streams and I am gonna fucking quit if doesn't
不行，Unix必须得有Stream，否则老子TMD就不干了
and that's awesome, so, we have Streams now, because of this crazy guy
酷毙了，归功于这个“疯子”，我们现在有了Stream
uh, but basicly Streams let you treat programs as just little pieces
简单来说，stream视程序为一段段代码片段
little pieces like garden hoses that you can just plumb together
就好比是花园中的软管，可以拼接在一起
I think plumbing metaphor a really apt for lot of this staff
我觉得这里用软管拼接的比喻相当贴切
so, the first kind of Streams that we have is readable Stream
首先要介绍的第一种stream是readable stream
and so, readable Streams are just event vendors that made a data event and an end event
readable stream其实就是事件提供商（event vendor），产生data事件和end事件
maybe some other one, those aren't important
也许不止如此，不过那些都不重要
uh, so, we can write a readable stream here
我们来举个readable stream的例子
vi start.js(explain: It seams like opening a file with vi editor)
vi start.js(备注: 用vi编辑器打开start.js文件)
ok, so, first thing you do, uh, you've probably seen this before
ok，首先要做的，也许你见过
uh, we fs.createReadStream and we can just like here I've got dictionary of like hundred thousand words
我们用fs.createReadStream，我这里有个字典文件，里面有很多单词
uh, and I can just pipe this just like in Unix was pipe stderr to stdout
然后，可以用pipe，就好比Unix中将stderr pipe到stdout
and if I run this, uh, cool, so I get light all of the words printed just on stdout
然后，执行它，酷！所有的单词都在stdout打印出来了
what's really cool about Streams is you don't you know buffer the whole thing into memory first. You just can incrementally output every single piece
stream真正酷的地方在于，你知道吗，不需要将所有的数据先全部载入到内存中。而是会一段段数据不间断地输出
uh, in the stream and that's really cool because you get results like immediately
在stream中，这真的很酷，因为（执行）结果就好像是即时获得的
and, Let you write a lot of really interesting abstractions in the some other things like  if you don't want stream to give up writing to stdout you do that about
除此之外，你还可以写出更加有意思的程序，比方说，如果不想让stream在stdout上写完数据后退出的话， 可以使用
uh, so, to write a stream like without just using a stream, it's a little bit more complicated
相比用stream而言，自己写一个stream有些许复杂
uh, the first you do for readable stream, and these little changes, so don't worry about memorizing all this.
对于readable stream，首先要做的，代码有少许改变，不过不用太担心，也不用去强记
the first thing you do is you set readable to true, the attribute
首先要做的就是将readable属性设置为true
uh, it's all here. I've got just this example, it just emits the data event and (the data) just has counter
这里就是这个简单例子所有的代码：它分发data事件，（数据）就是一个计数器
so, if you run that, ah, ah, ah, 5.js
如果运行5.js文件
cool, so in the very bottom down there, you can see this infinite string of digits
酷！在屏幕最下方，能看到一串无限长的数字
it's getting faster and faster, cuz, there are more digits and real numbers
并且输出速度越来越快，这是因为数字越来越多
but, uh, if we want to say end that after uh, after two seconds, we can just emit an end event.
不过，如果想要在两秒钟后停止的话，我们只要分发end事件即可
so, one, two and it's done!
好了，一秒、两秒，结束！
cool, so, what's really cool I mean besides the fact we can just pipe things around, uh.
酷！除了能够pipe数据之外，真正酷的还在于
we can actually also create writable stream since scratch
我们还能从头开始创建writable stream
so, like you probably, my hopefully, have seen this in Node if you used Node a lot
如果你对Node很熟悉，你或许（我也希望）对下面的代码很熟悉
fs.createWriteStream, it's awesome, because
fs.createWriteStream, 赞~
all you have to do is just write data to it
因为，剩下的就是往stream里面写数据
and it has been in a file, so you don't have to like have a big stream or big buffer like concat all these messages one by one on to some growing thing
由于这里已经是一个文件了，就没有像用一个大stream或者大的buffer来将 后续的数据拼接起来的必要了
you can just, uh, well, so I run this program and I cat output.txt
你只需……，好了，如果运行该程序，并cat output.txt（查看文件内容）
oh, cool, I have the same output as in my file
噢，酷！数据结果一样
uh, so another cool thing you can do is you can take readable streams like process.stdin as a standard readable streams and pipe them to your writable stream
还有一个很酷的就是：你可以将像process.stdin这样的readable stream视作标准的readable stream 并将其pipe给writable stream
so, if I run this program which is 2(.js)
如果运行2（.js）文件
then , abc, def, and we'll cat output.txt and see that it's exactly what we typed, so that's as we might expect
abc, def, 查看output.txt文件就会发现，其内容和我们输入的完全一致 和我们预期的一样
so, creating these writable streams since scratch is a bit more complicated
从头开始创建这类writable stream有点难度
so, the first thing we do is set writable to true
首先，将writable属性设置为true
this is used by pipe internally to make it, so that we can process.stdin.pipe to writable stream
这个属性是pipe内部使用的，这样我们就能process.stdin.pipe到writable stream了
so we said a writable stream and we set an end function and of course you have to be a little more careful in Node
我们有了writable stream，并设置了end函数，在Node中，此处要注意（选中的代码行）
cuz, it is just of convention, or you can call .end with an object
这只是种约定，你也可以调用end函数，并传入一个对象
and that we'll call .write, so that's just one thing to be a little careful of
我们调用.write，记得这里要留意下
but if you use some libraries that problem goes away
不过，如果使用一些第三方库的话，就没有这个问题了（库一般会处理掉）
so, if we run this program, we can do a similar kind of thing and here it's just log in all of the values that I am typing
好了，如果运行该程序，就能做类似的事情：将所有输入的内容打印出来
uh, if I end this stream, I get a handy little end message that accesses a mention point
如果结束stream，就能看到一个end!的提示消息
triple cool! So, we can actually do something useful here this custom writable stream.
超酷！事实上，我们可以利用自定义writable stream做更有用的事情
how about let's just count all the bytes and when the stream ends, we just print that out to stdout
比方说，我们来统计输入的字节数，并在stream结束时，将结果输出到stdout
so here write, you now have byte equal zero and call sequals the buf.length every time, at the end, I print byte count message
代码就在这里，首先从0开始，并且每次都加上buf.length，最后，输出字节总数
so, if I run this program, abc, def, and now I end it, and byte counts 8 which make sense because three and a new line is 4, and 4 is 8, cool!
运行该程序，abc，def，好，结束！结果输出字节总数为8 因为每行还有一个换行符（一行就是4个），酷！
so, that's writable stream.
好了，这就是writable stream
the next thing that I think is super important, to be realized is
下面要介绍的非常重要
this is an idea(a concept) I treat from Dominictarr who will be a recurring theme draft the sock
这是一个从Dominictarr借鉴过来的想法（概念）
it's called the through stream, so through stream is a readable wirtable stream
叫做through stream，through stream是readable writable stream
it's not the only kind of the readable writable stream, but it does as a readable writable stream that acts like a filter
它也并非是唯一的一种readable writable stream，不过，它工作方式像 readable writable stream（像过滤器（filter））
so, for instance, the grep program in Unix, you know, takes stdin and does some things and write stdout
举例来说，就好比是Unix中的grep，grep你应该知道吧， 它接收stdin作为输入，做一些处理之后，将结果输出到stdout
it's like from here to there
就好像：从这里到那里
so, we can make on these. If we create a new stream and we set both readable and writable to true
下面就让我们来实践下，我们创建一个新的stream，并将readable和writable都设为true
combining the previous two examples
结合前两个例子
we can have a write stream but we can also emit data
我们可以拥有一个write stream，但同时还可以分发data事件
and this is really cool, so, right here, I am uh just uppercasing the input that I get to make a loud stream
很酷吧！这里，我将输入的字符以大写形式输出，以此来形成一个“扩音”stream的效果
it'll be very loud for us, I did the same thing with the end
效果会很明显，对于end函数，我们处理和先前保持一样
and I'll pipe stdin to my ts, which should actually be called loud stream, like ls
接下来，将stdin pipe到ts，ts效果类似ls
so, that is 3.js, abc, hello lisboa and now end it
好了，运行3.js，abc，hello lisboa，然后结束！
oh, no, alright, I forgot to pipe that
噢，不！噢，对，我忘记pipe了
right, before, I had this, so, actually, I have to pipe the output somewhere for one to use it
好吧，此前，代码是这样的，事实上，这里还需要讲ts pipe到输出源
so I got 4.js and I'll say: beep boop and end it and we get uppercase messages
好了，现在有了4.js，输入：beep boop 然后结束 输出了大写形式的消息
great, indeed, this is the through stream
太棒了！这就是through stream
alright, and this was writable stream and this is through stream
好，这是writable stream、这是through stream
this is a kind of picture I drew to illustrate what's going on
这是一张我自己画的图，来解释刚刚发生的一切
so you have a function in the middle and you have thought these two little convertible machines that do the things
中间有个函数，两端是两个可互相转换的机器
the next kind of thing that I think is important to talk about is: pause stream
接下来要介绍的内容我觉得也很重要：pause stream
pause stream is a sort of through stream
pause stream也是一类through stream
well, in Node, there is a mechanism in pipe internally that helps you handle back nature
在Node中，pipe内部有一种机制，可以让你处理后续数据
you call .pause and resume when you want to start it again a sort of like barrier a few green water and then you turn on the tap to get new something
调用pause暂停，并当想要重新开始获取数据时，就调用.resume， 就好比是出水口有个阀门，关闭就不出水，打开就出水
plumbing plumbing metaphors there if useful
可以用水管互相连接来做比喻，如果这有助于理解的话
so, I have an example for a pause stream
这里有一个pause stream的例子
here we can look at it
我们来看下
so, this is an http server that creates this output.txt file with all of the content that we put out here
这是一个http服务器，它将我们的输入都写到output.txt文件
so, I am gonna echo beep boop and I'll curl that and finally run this program
我首先echo beep boop，接着用curl，最后运行该程序
so, node 0.js and this program I'll curl -sSNT- localhost:3000 and so, told me ok
node 0.js，接着输入curl -sSNT- localhost:3000 看到了ok
and now it should have written using the writable stream to output.txt
现在，输入的内容应当已经通过writable stream写到output.txt文件中了
so, we cat that out, oh, cool, we see our message
好，我们cat出来看看，酷！看到了！
super great, but, suppose our requirements change in this program
超赞！但是，假设这个时候需求变更了
so, maybe we have to make a directory before we can actually put the data somewhere
假设现在要在写数据前需要先创建一个文件夹
so, we have to call fs.mkdir with like a random id
这个时候，我们就不得不调用fs.mkdir，并用一个随机的id来表示文件夹名字
so, it will take this code to generate id and we'll put fs.mkdir on that
所以，这段代码用来生成id，并将fs.mkdir放在这里
ok, this seems we work through,right?
好，应该差不多了，对吧？
woo, see, the same thing and instead of telling res.end('ok') we write res.end with the id
唔，看下，同样的，这里不再是res.end('ok')，而是以id结束
so, it should tell us, Oops, and I need to write the right file
好，结果应该是，哦不，貌似写多文件了
node 2.js, correct!
node 2.js, 就是它!
ok, so node 2.js, ok, cool, so now gives this the id and it should be in data directory and output.txt file
好，node 2.js，ok，酷！结果显示了id，数据就应该在数据目录下的output.txt文件中了
holy crappy, it's empty! what's going on here?
尼玛，居然是空的！怎么回事？
let's just try that again, maybe, maybe it works this time
我们再来试下，也许这次就好了
uh, ok, so, we can cat out that, ok, so that time works! that's a little weird.
好，果然好了！有点诡异
uh, it wasn't an accident. There is some risk condition in this code.
这并非“事故”，而是我们的代码有bug隐患
we are calling fs.mkdir and then we are piping to a writable stream
我们先调用fs.mkdir，然后pipe到writable stream
so, you know, you can get in the case where you know data events have come in before our callback fires of the fs.mkdir
问题来了，如果data事件在fs.mkdir的回调前就分发了，就会出现问题
how do we get around this? Pause stream of course
那么怎么解决这个问题呢？答案当然是 pause stream
if we alter a clutter a little bit, to do...
我们只要稍微改下代码，就……
alright, so, we required of course first, it's called pause-stream on NPM
好，首先咱们要引入一个叫pause-stream的模块
alright, and so, we make one and we'll pause it
然后，创建一个pause stream，将其暂停
and then, instead of piping our request to the ws object
然后，这次不是将request pipe给ws对象
we will pipe it..., ok, ps.pipe, let me just jump the last worked on
而是pipe给…… ps.pipe，让我先回到上个版本
ok, so we pipe a pause stream instead of the write stream
好，我们pipe pause stream而不是write stream
and it's pausing and then, at the end, we call resume to resume it once the callback is actually fired
它暂停了，随后，在最后，回调函数触发后，我们调用resume来恢复stream
not like eventually, you know, maybe some data is passed, maybe not now we actually resume it. pause stream will buffer the data for us
在恢复stream的时候，也许数据已经过来了，也许还没有。pause stream会将数据buffer起来
so, if we take our existing example and run updated version and we curl to it
继续刚刚这个例子，这次运行更新后的版本，然后用curl
so, cat out this output, make sure ok, work that time
再看看output文件，确认没错，这次对了
so, you might notice this prints out the id
你可能已经注意到了，服务器会返回id
so, we can actually cat data, do some like Unix aggregator there output.txt
所以，事实上，我们可以使用Unix的聚合（aggregator），来打印output.txt中的数据
ok, so now it's catting the file that is the outputs
好，这就在输出文件内容
and now, as you can see, every single time, we get the correct output
如你所见，现在每次都能够获得正确的输出结果
we just eliminate that risk condition where we get data with pause stream
上述就是使用pause stream来规避此前获取数据的问题
pause stream is great
pause stream很赞
so, Oops, the next thing is duplex streams
好，下面要闪亮登场的是duplex stream
duplex streams are also readable writable stream
duplex stream也是readable writable stream
but, duplex streams are really cool because they are like a telephone you know
不过，duplex非常酷，因为它很想电话
it's not just a filter like grep like through stream
它不仅仅像through stream那样是一个过滤器（如grep）
but it's like a sort of conversation
它更像是“谈话”
you have site A talks to site B, but then site B needs like talk back to site A
比方说，A要和B通话，这个时候，B也需要和A通话
and sort of these circular ongoing communication
就像这类循环的实时通讯
if you see, a.pipe(b).pipe(a) or something like that
如屏幕所示，a.pipe(b).pipe(a) 诸如此类
you probably, you most definitely have a duplex stream
也许，不，应该是你肯定用过duplex stream
so, and uh, there's sweet module called duplexer that was actually taking out of the module called event-stream
有个很好的模块叫duplexer，它衍生自event-stream模块
that let you take like readable stream and writable stream and like smooch them together into a duplex stream
它可以将readable stream和writable stream合成到一个duplex stream中
duplex streams are sort of like the voltron of streams in that respect
从某种意义上来说，duplex可以说是stream之王
especially when you have a request and response object you can serve like plumb them together to make this duplex stream
特别是当你有一个request对象和response对象时，就可以将两者拼接起来，形成一个duplex stream
and that's really cool because you can take like other duplex stream and take the request and response pipe that to another stream and pipe that back to the duplex
这样很酷，因为你可以将其他的duplex stream以及request、response对象拼接在一起 再将其拼接到另外一个stream上，然后再拼回到duplex stream
because duplex is awesome and like that
duplex真的超赞
it's... you'll see a lot of that. I actually skip this section
在后面会看到很多duplex stream，这里暂且先跳过
so, another kind of through stream that I definitely definitely wanna talk about is called JSONStream
好了，另外一种through stream，我一定，一定要介绍的，就是JSONStream
JSONStream is really awesome
JSONStream也超赞！
so, suppose I have a 125Mb JSON file for all of the property boundaries in San Francisco
假设这里有一个125Mb大的文件，包含了旧金山的所有的地界信息
this file exists and it's awesome, I've rendered it it took like three hours
真的有这个文件哦，我花了将近3小时才搞定
so, like, if we just straight up, if we just straight up like try to load this into the memory
如果，我们“霸王硬上功”——直接讲其载入到内存中
you'll gonna wait a long time
你非得等上一段很长的时间不可
that takes like several minutes, it's actually loaded
完全载入，也许得花上几分钟的时间，
but if we use the power of streams here with this module called JSONStream
而如果我们这里发挥stream的威力，使用JSONStream模块的话
we can actually make some progress
会提升不少（时间短很多）
so, say going back to the streams, set the value we want to get
回到stream，设置我们要获取的值
is the coordinates data, that's inside of the features key, but that's inside of the geometry key
是坐标（coordinates）属性，该属性在features键中，features中geometry键
but that's inside of the coordinates key, the coordinates key is the thing we actually wanna use
里面有coordinates键，coordinates键就是我们真正需要的数据
so, how do we do that, we use JSONStream and JSONStream.parse takes an array of sort like key/values
那么，怎么做呢？我们用JSONStream，JSONStream.parse，该方法接收一个包含类似键/值形式的数组作为参数
not just key/values, you can actually have like some patterns or anything
事实上不仅仅是键/值，还可以用一些模式等
so, "features" is actually an array, so, if we've gonna every element, we can specify true instead of string name
“features”是一个数组，所以，如果我们需要数组所有的元素，就可以简单的指定true即可， 无需将所有的名字列出来
and we can lookup the geometry key, we can look up the coordinates key
接下来是geometry键，然后是coordinates键
and we can just console.dir the values, and take a read stream and pipe that into the parser here
我们只需用console.dir将值打印出来，并将一个read stream pipe给parser
and so , if I run that program, maybe I forget a step here
好了，运行该程序，也许少了一步
oh, I am still in the pause-stream example, that's why you guys should come on that
噢，我还在pause stream的例子中，这就是为啥没有反应
ok, if I run this example, ok, sweet
好，再次运行该程序，好，酷！
so, instead of just you know, fs.readFile('citylots.json'), we don't have to wait for that to load the whole damn thing into the memory
和fs.readFile('citylots.json')不同， 我们不用将所有的数据都载入内存
we can just like start processing it, right away
我们直接就可以处理
and what's really cool too is what we can is actually stream
非常酷吧，stream好样的！
so, suppose we'll gonna make like some vast transformation that's gonna read an stream and like write back out to a file
再来做些改动，假设我们这次需要从stream中读取数据，并将其写回到文件中
no problem, we can use JSONStream.stringify for that, that's exactly a kind of this part but streaming for JSON
没问题，我们可以用JSONStream.stringify 这和JSON的stringify类似，只是是stream的方式
so, we can do stringify.pipe to a write stream, here coords.json
我们可以stringify.pipe 到一个write stream，这里就是coords.json文件
and so, if I run this file, which is 9.js
好，我们运行9.js
ok, it's just sitting there, that's because it's actually writing to this file coords.json
卡住了，这是因为正在往coords.json文件中写数据
and if we munch that, it's actually growing continuouslly
如果我们查看下文件内容的字数，就会发现在不断增长
that's because our stream is letting it do that you know, we don't have to buffer the whole thing in the memory
这是因为stream正在工作，我们不需要将整个一大坨数据加载到内存中
which is really really important if you're writing scalable web services
这对于书写可伸缩的web服务而言，非常非常的重要
which if you're writing Node, that's worth you are really good at
尤其是写Node的时候，应当要非常擅长处理这类事情
so, uh, yes, you use JSONStream parsers where possible
记得在适用的场景下，尽可能的使用JSONStream
so, the next crazy thing that I want to show you is called scuttlebutt
好，下一个要展示的，酷毙了的东西叫scuttlebutt
scuttlebutt is ..., ok, yes, dnode is another example of duplex stream
scuttlebutt是…… 哦，对了，dnode也属于duplex stream一例
which we'll get to a little bit with the craziness
dnode会在后面我要展示的“碉堡”了的demo充当重要角色
still to come, so, scuttlebutt is, the term comes to term not cool term for water cool basically
言归正传，scuttlebutt并非是指和水相关的装置
so, scuttlebutt is a gossip protocol, that where you have all of these nodes and network sort of like talk with each other
这里的scuttlebutt是一种gossip协议，用来使得网络中不同节点间能够通讯
and there's not like canonical source of data, they sort of just pass messages around
它没有标准的数据源，而只是到处传递消息
in order to have an entire state and it's eventually consistent, which is awesome, it's history based algorithm
为了同步状态，这很酷，它属于一种基于历史的算法（history based algorithm）
it's crazy awesome, so, to use scuttlebutt
应该说这超赞，好，要使用scuttlebutt
here I am just using the scuttlebutt model and if you like more practical example, you can actually checkout this module called crdt
这里我只使用scuttlebutt模型，如果要看更多相关的例子，可以看一个叫crdt的模块
but, so, scuttlebutt models, you can just create some streams for each of them
通过scuttlebutt模型, 每个模型都可以创建stream
and, like set a value here, set a value on node A pipe that to node B
这里，在A节点上设置一个值，并将它pipe给B节点
if we run this, cool, so, we actually got the event on node B even though we set the value on node A
运行该程序，酷！尽管我们是在节点A上设置的值，但是我们可以在节点B上捕获到事件
and we are just piping here, so we can actually do that over network connection
这里我们只是pipe出去，事实上，我们可以将其用在网络连接上
so, here I create a http server, and we'll just do similar thing where we sort of have keys and values
这里，创建一个http服务器，然后做些类似设置值，取值的操作
and this part is really cool, so if we ... the first argument is port number
这部分很酷，如果我…… 第一个参数是端口号
so we listen on port 8000 and we can curl to this
所以，我们监听8000端口，并利用curl向该端口发送http请求
so, that's getting key a, but I can set it for printing equals
这条命令是获取键a的值（结果是undefined），这里还可以设置键a的值
now, I get key a, it's 5, that's neat and I can do that as much as I want
现在我获取到了键a的值为5，非常简单，想怎么设就怎么设，想设多少就设多少
but if I spin up another server on port 8001 and connect that with scuttlebutt to port 8000
然而，如果我再起一台服务器，监听8001端口，并将其通过scuttlebutt和8000端口上的服务器相连
now I can curl localhost:8001 key a, that's the same and I can actually set it to new value
这时，我就能通过curl localhost:8001/a 也能获取到a的值，当然，还可以通过8001上的服务器给a设置新值
and get it on port 8000 and that value is proper got
然后再从8000端口上的服务器获取a的值，也获得了最新的值
but it's cooler, because we can actually connect, it's not just like a client-server thing
很酷吧，不过远不止如此，我们并非只能连接客户端-服务器端
we can actually connect ..., here I'll spin up a new server on port 8002, but I only connect it to ... port 8002 to port 8001
事实上，还可以连接……这里，我新起一台监听8002的服务器，但，我只将其和8001端口上的服务器相连
and if I turn to get ..., if I turn to set a value on 8002
这是，如果我尝试获取……，如果我在8002上设置a的值
and then I get it on 8000, it should be the same value and it is!
随后在8000上获取它，应该能够获取到相同的值，哈哈，如我所言！
this is because ... so, the server on 8002 is not directly connected to 8000, it's only connected through the server 8001
这是因为……，8002端口上的服务器并没有直接和8000端口上的服务器相连，它只和8001上的相连
so, basically, if you have connectedness in your graph of streams that where everything is piped together
好，简单来说，只要stream互相之间能够连通
the whole state of the entire network be eventually consistent
那么整个网络中结点的状态最终都会同步
you can just set values and get them elsewhere
你只需要在此处设置，就能随时从彼处取值
and you don't have to worry about like caving client and server and how to caving a cluster of database peered to each other
无需担心，类似于如何同步客户端和服务端、如何保证数据库cluster结点间如何做数据一致
which, I'll totally rush to next part is ... skipping that
好，下面将全面进入下一部分，那就是……（跳过这里）
this craziness
这部分非常精彩
so, don't worry, I'll go very fast and it'll be so awesome
不用担心，我会很快给大家演示，保证让你们目瞪口呆
so, let's build a streaming web app that synchronizes state across all users
我们来构建一个streaming web应用，该应用功能如下：同步所有用户的状态；
listens for server events, has an rpc control interface
监听服务器端事件；rpc控制接口；
runs multiple streams over mux-demux, in node and the browser
通过mux-demux在node端和浏览器端运行多个stream；
and load balanced across multiple web servers that peering with each other over scuttlebutt which is gossip protocol
并且在多台web服务器之间做负载均衡，使用scuttlebutt（gossip协议）
ok, that sounds awesome, let's do it
好了，听起来很赞吧，那就开始吧
so, the first thing we need to do is well, we'll create a scuttlebutt model and we'll create a web server
首先要做的就是创建一个scuttlebutt模型，并创建一个web服务器
and here the web server just listens on the port
这里，web服务器就只监听在（指定的）端口
well, what happened, it was gonna too fast, that's crazy
嗯？什么情况？可能是太快了
ok, so, we create a web server, we'll create a stream
好了，我们创建一个web服务器，创建一个stream
and then, we can just add a thing here
接下来，我们只需在这里加一样东西
so, if you are familiar with couchdb, it has sweet replicate api but what we can succeed about it is
知道couchdb吧，它的api很赞，不过，我们能做的更赞，那就是
you can only ... it's lot of only ... it's fully like servers connecting clients
就像是服务器和客户端连接
but, with this, anybody can connect to our server, replicate and not only replicate from us but replicate to us
但，我们这里，任何人都可以连接到我们的服务器，复制状态，这里不仅仅是从我们这里复制，还能复制给我们
and that information will be passed around our entire network over streams, it would be, it's gonna be really awesome
状态信息会通过streams，在整个网络间传递，这简直酷毙了
ok, so, some other thing, we'll use this module I wrote called emit-stream to turn a event emitter into a stream and back into an event emitter again
好，另外，我们还要用到一个我写的叫emit-stream的模块，用来将事件分发器和stream进行互相转化
so, we can use other crazy awesome module called mux-demux which is mentioned earlier today, which is awesome
我们还会用到此前提过的，叫mux-demux的模块，这个模块很赞
and that let us take multiple streams, pack them into a single stream and I have a picture of this
它能将多个stream，封装成一个stream，我画了一张图来对其做解释说明
well, that's emit-stream, oh, where is my picture, it was awesome anyway, it doesn't matter
这是emit-stream，我的图片在哪里？好吧，它肯定在，不管了，没关系
so, we have a mux-demux and that just like is a crazy video thing
好，我们有了mux-demux，它就像一个神物
so, whatever mux-demux, we'll create a stream called state that's for our synchronization
通过mux-demux，我们创建一个名为state的stream，用来做同步
and we can create another stream called events that's for our event system
我们再创建另外一个叫events的stream用于系统事件
which will turn an event emitter into a stream back to an event emitter on the other side and  vice versa
它会将事件分发器转变为stream，在另一端则将stream变为事件分发器，反之亦然
ok, cool, so, the other thing we can do is actually emit events
好，酷！另外要做的就是分发事件
and we can emit like a part event also when the request ends it's a kind cool
当请求结束时，我们分发“part”事件，有意思吧
so, this part is really freaking awesome
这部分真心赞！
so, we have this, you know that slices string that I show you
看这里，我们将字符串切割成数组
so, now , for every additional argument passed the initial argument that I give which is the port number
现在，所有端口号之后额外的参数
it'll connect and replicate with in a period of fashion every other web server
都指定了和其他参数端口上web服务器相连接
so, we can just tight multiple web servers, they all talk to each other
所以，我们只要起多台web server，它们互相之间都会通讯
they all use gossip protocol to communicate, all of the state across all of the network are eventually consistent
它们使用gossip协议来通讯，所有服务器之间的状态都会同步
and we can plug this directly into browsers also, which is the next part
这部分代码可以直接放到浏览器端，下部分会介绍
so, after some login staff, yeah, here is our web server
登录之后，对，这就是我们的web服务器
and, yes, we can use shoe, which is a module that I wrote all it is is really thin wrapper on top of sockjs that give you a stream
我们可以用shoe，这也是我自己写的模块，它其实就是讲sockjs做了封装，提供了stream功能
that's all it does. that's amazing, you don't have to have like weird thing, you can just use modules, let's do that
它干的就这么多。但却很酷，你无需关心旁枝末节，用模块就是，来吧
so, we have our stream right, and all we need to do to replicate is stream.pipe(createStream()).pipe(stream)
好了，stream准备就绪，我们还需要做的复制工作就是stream.pipe(createStream()).pipe(stream)
and that's the mux-demux connection， it's exactly the same as our http streaming connection to replicate the states
这是mux-demux连接，这和我们http streaming连接是一样的，都是用来复制（不同结点间）状态的
so, we wrote a function, it'll turn a string, we can use that anywhere to replicate anywhere browsers, servers like other servers
好了，我们写了一个函数，用于创建stream，然后，用它在任何地方（浏览器、服务器/其他服务器）来复制状态
it doesn't matter, we just send data and the network figures it out
我们只需要发送数据即可，轻松愉快，接下来的事情，网络间不同结点会自动同步
so, there's some plumbing in here too
这里还有一件事情
I snuck dnode into this example also because just why not
这个例子中还用了dnode，理由就是：为什么不用呢？！
here I have a function that I just defined and you know, it's dnode
这里，用dnode定义了一个函数
so, and with mux-demux, all I have to do is create an additional stream, and just like pipe it through
有了mux-demux，我要做的就是再创建一个stream，将它pipe出去
and that's all, so, to recapitulate a little bit
好了，完工！简单回顾下
we have dnode stream, we've got mux-demux
我们有dnode stream、mux-demux
here's our browser code actually to render this
这里是浏览器部分的代码，用来渲染
so, it draws a big blue box and what's really cool is we are using actually exactly the same modules
它负责绘制一个蓝色的大盒子，这里很酷的地方在于，我们用了同样的模块
we won't actually know except for maybe there is document.body, this is actually browser code
要不是这里有document.body这样的代码，恐怕很难看出这是浏览器端的代码吧
cuz we're using scuttlebutt, we're using mux-demux
我们用了scuttlebutt、mux-demux
it's all just browser fights up, we're using emit-stream just the same
这些都是在浏览器端用哦~，还有emit-stream也不例外
it's pretty much the same code except it has dom staff in it
除了dom操作部分的代码，其余代码几乎完全一样
so, we'll go through all of this, we just recap here a little bit and I'll actually run it and it'll be done
好了，以上就是简单的代码回顾，等下我会运行这个例子，然后……就没有然后了（结束了）
so, we synchronize state across all uses, we listen for server events with the emit-stream
我们同步所有用户状态、用emit-stream监听服务器端事件
we run multiple streams over mux-demux, we load balanced across multiple servers
通过mux-demux运行多个streams，以及在不同服务器间做负载均很
so, I am telling you I haven't actually demonstrate this yet
这里还缺一个
in order a browser, we have an rpc control interface with dnode so that's the all the things
浏览器这边，我们用dnode来实现rpc接口调用，好了，全部完成
so, let's actually run this beast
让我们来启动这个“怪物”吧
so, the first thing I'll do is I'll browserify the last version that wasn't any good
首先要browserify最新版本代码
so, staticbundle.js cuz I think I was messing with that earlier and I'll run the server on port 8000
staticbundle.js，启动服务器并监听8000端口
cool, and I can visit it, HOLA LISBOA, that's from dnode actually
酷！可以访问了，HOLA LISBOA, 这是dnode在工作
and here we just have a box, the box, it's not very fancy
这里我们就只有一个盒子而已，还不够炫
all you can do is drag it, right?
能做的就是拖拽，对吧？
but, if we have another user connected, and if I make it smaller again
但是，当另外一个用户进来之后，我把它缩小点
goodness, ok, so if I move the box over here, cool if I move it there from over here
好，如果我把盒子移到这里，酷~~，如果从这里移动到那里
you might have seen something like socket.io, and that's great that's reusable
也许你已经闻到了socket.io的味道了吧，这很赞，重用性很高
but, that's not intereasting enough
不过，这还不够有趣
let's actually have a load balanced server
让我们来点负载均衡
so, we'll run another server on port 8001 and connect it to other server on 8002, connected over stream and over everything
我们在8001端口起一台服务器，并通过stream，将其和8000端口上的服务器相连
so, oh, godness, it's a little bugness, oh no, damn it work damn it
噢，我的天！有些小bug，哦，不，求你了，工作吧，工作吧！
I am telling you this totally worked earlier, sort of oh, there it goes, yes, it totally is working kind of a little bit
我发誓它之前是好的，貌似……，噢，好了，工作了，尽管有些小瑕疵
it's bug there but like, that's the basic idea
尽管有bug，不过意思到了，这里就是展现一种思路和想法
that is all that I have to say, we'll skip some pictures, use all of these modules, they are amazing
好了，这就是我要讲的所有内容，我们再来看些描述模块的图片，它们真的非常赞
thanks!
谢谢！